Juan Manuel Vergara

Argentina | +543434054038 jnmvrgr@gmail.com

Summary

As a passionate and dedicated Full Stack Developer with +2 years of experience, I bring a deep love for both Frontend and Backend development to the table. With a meticulous and highly organized approach, I thrive as a collaborative team player. I constantly seek personal and professional growth, continuously exploring new tools and technologies to enhance my skillset. What sets me apart is my unwavering commitment to best practices and excellence in project delivery. I strive for perfection, ensuring that projects are not only successfully completed but also meet the highest standards of quality. With my skills, attitude, and dedication to personal and professional growth, I am confident in making a valuable contribution to any team. I possess the drive for innovation and the pursuit of excellence that can positively impact projects and organizations. Let me bring my passion and expertise to help your team succeed.

Experience

Scale AI

Software Developer | 05/2023 - Present

- As part of the Generative AI team, I analyze code samples written in Java, JavaScript, TypeScript and Python, which are generated by a Large Language Model. These code samples include web applications, AI implementations, data structures and algorithms.
- Quantifying and ranking responses generated by the LLM in terms of quality, precision, and structure.
- Writing and editing code written by the LLM with reasoning to fix bugs and improve performance.

Coderhouse

Backend Tutor | 05/2023 - 10/2023

- Reviewing materials prior to class
- · Resolving doubts through Zoom chat.
- Participating in the Warm Up and Catch Up meeting.
- Responding to individual inquiries through the platform's chat.
- Correcting Deliverables/Pre-deliveries.
- Providing feedback on Deliverables/Pre-deliveries.

Mathison Projects, INC

Full Stack Developer | 08/2022 - 06/2023

Developed a comprehensive social media management and scheduling application. Completed tasks:

- Responsive landing page and website.
- Auth system. Include social login with: Instagram, Facebook, Twitter, Google, LinkedIn, TikTok and Pinterest.
- Create and manage clients. Link social media accounts: Instagram, Facebook, Twitter, Google, LinkedIn, TikTok, Pinterest.
- Payment system with Stripe.
- Convenient scheduling and publishing of posts using a calendar.
- Create a dashboard with charts for analytics.
- Access to insightful analytics.
- Create a Help Desk with Chat Bot powered by open-source AI technology.
- Implement Scrum methodology for efficient and effective project management.

Developed main functionalities for MVP. The technologies used were: React, Next, JavaScript, TypeScript, Strapi, Node, AWS, Git, and GPT 3.5.

Virtual Office Systems

Full Stack Developer | 04/2022 - 09/2022

Developed a mobile and web application for connecting carriers with clients and companies to facilitate mass product distribution. Completed tasks:

- Develop both the Frontend and Backend components of the app.
- Develop individual mobile apps for carriers, clients, and companies.
- Auth system.
- Integrate real time chat to connect carriers, clients, and companies.
- Upload, edit and view documents.
- Add geolocalization and best routes for carriers.

Delivered a high-performance application that met the client's requirements. The technologies used were: React Native (Expo), Node.js, MySQL, Docker, and Git.

Education

Henry Bootcamp
Full Stack Developer | 03/2022
Certificate

Projects

• Minecraft Clone

Developed a basic clone of Minecraft using JavaScript, React, and Three.js. You can add or remove blocks, jump, run, change block types, and more. You can also save your world and load it whenever you want.

• Resident Evil Wiki

Developed a wiki for Resident Evil games and history. It's an SPA that, when you start scrolling, you will begin immersing yourself in the Resident Evil universe, starting from the first game and progressing through all canon games enumerated in the saga. You can view the epilogue of every game and the list of characters. You can select a character from the list to see their summary and role in the game. Each game is accompanied by relevant images. It is also mobile responsive. The technologies used were: TypeScript, Next, React, TailwindCSS and Gsap.

· Crypto App

Using the CoinGecko API, you can view the real-time prices of all cryptocurrencies in ranking order. By tapping on any token, you can access a chart and apply filters for different time periods such as days, months, or all-time, as well as add it to your watchlist. Additionally, you have the ability to create a personalized portfolio to track the real-time prices of all your tokens. The technologies utilized for this project include React Native, Expo, React Navigation, and Recoil.

MovieMark

This group project was carried out for the Henry bootcamp, focusing on creating an ecommerce platform for a cinema. The platform includes features such as user registration and login, browsing and searching for upcoming and top-rated premiere movies, accessing detailed movie information, searching for groceries, adding tickets or groceries to the shopping cart, and making payments via MercadoPago. Additionally, we developed a comprehensive admin panel that allows for efficient management of movies, groceries, and users. The technologies employed in this project include React.js, Redux, and SASS for the Frontend, and Node.js (Express) with PostgreSQL (connected via Sequelize) for the Backend.

Skills

JavaScript, Java, Python, TypeScript, Node.js, Express.js, React, Next.js, Redux, React Native, SQL, MongoDB, HTML5, CSS3, Git, AWS, Redis, Docker, SaaS, Scrum

Languages

English, Spanish, Portuguese

Links

LinkedIn

Portfolio